Hello, in today's video
I will show you how it was possible to execute commands on
GitHub server using a malicious YAML file.
It allowed to steal all the source code stored on the server.
The vulnerability was found and reported by William Bowling
and he got $25,000 for it.
He also has more write-ups about hacking GitHub on his blog,
make sure to check that out. But for now enjoy the video!
Probably most of you already know what's GitHub.
It's a place for storage and version control of the source code.
GitHub pages is a service that allows to serve static
websites from GitHub repositories.
It's available both in the global GitHub instance and in
GitHub Enterprise and the latter one was vulnerable to this
attack. Jekyll is a software used for generating static websites
that can be used on GitHub Pages. Static websites are the
ones that do not process user input.
It could be just a set of HTML files, but then to each file
you would have to copy your header and footer, so it would
be better to use some kind of a template.
And that's exactly what the Jekyll is used for - for creating
static websites from templates.
It uses markdown to create those templates. And markdown is
a really simple language that allows creation of HTML websites.
In its base version,
It looks like this:
And the amount of options is really limited.
So there are extended versions of markdown and kramdown is
one of them. It gives the user more ability to style his website,
but most importantly for us, it also allows to specify some
options for the parser.
It can be used in a few different ways,
but GitHub used it as a ruby library.
Jekyll uses _config.yml file for storing configuration
options, including the ones for the kramdown parser.
And while looking at the source code of the library, the
researcher noticed input option that was not described in
the documentation.
The parser took this input option made the first letter capital
and called function try_require. And hat function created
a path kramdown/parser/:input tried to import
that file.
The idea was to give the user the ability to use different
parsers from kramdown/parsers/ directory.
However, this function did not forbid putting in ../
sequence in this input option, making it possible to
perform a directory traversal attack.
The way Ruby import works is that it executes the file straight
away after importing, even before you call any function. It works
the same way in Python and that's why if __name__ == "__main__".
is commonly used there.
That means that we can import arbitrary Ruby file from the
server and it will be executed.
But first we need to upload our Ruby file onto the server
into the location known by us.
And this is not a trivial task, because files from the repositories
are stored in hashed locations, which means that we cannot
use them because we cannot predict where they are.
The researcher tested it on his own version of GitHub Enterprise,
which means that he had access to
the server and he used opensnoop tool to see what files are
being opened on the server and he noticed that before being
transferred to the hashed location, files are being put into
the temporary directory.
But the path of the directory was fully predictable making
our attack more feasible. But those files were very quickly
deleted and you'd have to be very very lucky
to hit the import at the moment when they are still present.
But in this kinda race condition, you can extend the time
window you have by creating files that will take more time
to be processed.
And that's exactly what the researcher did.
He created five 100 megabyte files.
And in the infinite Loop pushed it along with the Ruby file.
Then, after about a minute.
He noticed that the Ruby file got executed. And by having
the ability to execute code on the server,
you can easily steal or information that's stored there.
And after reporting the issue the researcher found yet another
set of options that let to the same kind of attack and reported
it as well.
The vulnerability was fixed and right now,
the vulnerability is no longer exploitable in the newest
version of GitHub Enterprise.
The reward for that was $20,000 plus 5,000 bonus.
And that's it for today's video.
Lately, there are a lot of vulnerabilities affecting YAML files,
so that is definitely something we should learn and if you
have learned something from this video leave a like and leave
a subscription if you haven't already. But for now, thanks
for watching and goodbye!